# Sean P. Moroney

Cell: 440-622-2818 E-mail: spmoroney@att.net

#### SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Software Developer and Programmer with strong analytical and problem-solving skills. Highly adaptable and detail oriented with the ability to work independently or on a team to create user-friendly systems and applications. Able to rapidly learn advanced concepts and technology on the fly to bring my best energy each day. Experience in:

- Application Development
- Software Engineering
- Coding
- Troubleshooting
- Software Development Life Cycle (SLDC)
- Testing/Debugging

- Documentation
- Databases
- User Interface/Training
- Agile Processes (Kanban, Scrum)

### **EDUCATION**

Case Western Reserve University, School of Engineering – B.S., Computer Science, 2016

#### **TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE AND PROFICIENCIES**

Languages: Visual Basic, Java, C#, SQL, Angular

Software: Word, Excel, Power Point, IDE (Visual Studio), Windows Installer XML (WiX), Jira,

Confluence, SQL Server

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

Coursework: Microsoft Azure, JavaScript, REST API

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Hyland Software - Cleveland, OH

2017-Present

Enterprise content management software for national/international companies, non-profits, schools, financial service firms, and hospital systems.

#### Developer

- Sole resource responsible for coding, maintaining, and troubleshooting code for 300+ projects, ensuring high code quality and improved customer satisfaction.
- Prioritized and multi-tasked work items in parallel to address customer and enterprise issues in a timely fashion.
- Created and updated documentation for knowledge sharing of team processes, providing access to it through Confluence.
- Advocated for process changes and managed continuous improvement strategies to increase the efficiency of the products' installers.
- Designed and implemented a strategy to transition 280 installer projects to product team ownership, allowing knowledge transfer and hand-off for localized team management.
- Supported multiple products to enable teams to focus on enhancing the user experience.
- Collaborated with a distributed, cross-functional team and worked directly with tech support and customers to complete tasks in an agile environment, which helped develop the team's relationship.
- As the subject matter expert in my area, mentored new team members in concepts and processes.
- Provided clear communication/training to people with technical/non-technical backgrounds.

#### iStrab, CWRU Incubator - Cleveland, OH

2016

A sensory medical device to diagnose vision disorders business startup.

#### **Systems Analyst**

- Worked in an entrepreneurial pre-launch environment to rapidly learn and build a new type of system for a first of its kind medical application.
- Lead troubleshooter and tester for software running on a Linux operating system utilizing C++ language, including identifying and fixing runtime/compile errors.
- Co-created comprehensive documentation, including software requirements, design/technical documents, installation guide and user instruction so that the program could be understood by end users.
- Problem-solved issues with transferability of software to multiple platforms, which made the software more portable.

### **ROCKWELL AUTOMATION - Cleveland, OH**

2014-2015

2012-2016

Automated processes for industrial manufacturing

## **Operations and Engineering Services Department Intern**

- Created an automated process to replace an outdated manual method. Used Visual Basic and Microsoft Excel with data provided from electrical design software.
- Determined system requirements and performed verification tests in collaboration with stakeholders and future users of the process.
- Independently solved problems, provided status updates, and completed projects ahead of schedule.
- Made a presentation to the executive team that clearly articulated the details of the automated process. The finished process was well received by business partners and projected to save more than \$500,000 annually.

### CASE WESTERN RESERVE UNIVERSITY - Cleveland, OH

Completed numerous projects as a Computer Science major in undergraduate courses, including:

- Collaborated on a database design utilizing SQL including content, properties and query procedures.
- Co-designed a Java based software system with version controls in Git, including identifying system requirements, design, coding, testing and documentation.
- Created an interpreter to execute a simulated object-oriented programming language.
- Completed complex projects in a Java based framework to enable the computer to win strategy games. Utilized A.I. algorithms ranging from simple searches to machine learning.
- Applied Java to create advanced digital logic and teaching utilities in Minecraft.

#### **VOLUNTEER AND LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE**

#### YOUNG CATHOLIC PROFESSIONALS - Cleveland, OH

2020-Present

A national organization dedicated to increasing respect and inclusivity in the workplace.

#### **Director of Technology**

- Created social media postings to advertise the organization and events.
- Managed technology for virtual, interactive events.
- Coordinated with other members of the leadership team to plan events and improve outreach.

### PRIVATE TECHNICAL PROFESSIONAL NETWORK

2021-Present

- Established a thriving technical community with 100+ active participants daily.
- Facilitates efficient communication and collaboration amongst colleagues to share knowledge, build connections, and network.
- 300+ members in total.

#### **HACKER SOCIETY**

2015 - 2016

 Dedicated to developing the skills needed to produce software for business, manufacturing, and scientific applications.